If you've got the time
and the stomach for it,
I've got a story for you.
A tale of magic and witches,
of quests and of monsters.
Of good and of evil.
But make no mistake.
This is no fairy tale.
And there are no happy endings.
The world you know is gone,
consumed by the flames
of a great war long ago
when death
rained from the sky.
All that's left now
are the Lost Lands,
filled with twisted creatures
that dwell in the shadows.
What remains of humanity
takes refuge in a single city.
Long ago, a mysterious witch,
Gray Alys,
emerged from the Lost Lands.
This is the story
of how we met
and how she saved
the both of us.
Stop your work!
Let this be an example to all.
No one shall defy the church.
They say you can buy anything
you might desire from Gray Alys.
But it's better not to.
And still the people
seek your help.
They're ignorant, uneducated.
Some are poor, some rich.
All are desperate.
I refuse no one.
Do you know what the church says
about the likes of you?
I'm sure
you're going to tell me.
That you are of the devil
and it's our duty
to root you out.
In the name of the Overlord,
ruler of
the City Under The Mountain,
High Priest of the Faith,
I sentence you, Gray Alys,
to death by hanging.
Repent, woman.
What is happening to me?
You cannot be trusted.
You're a slave to the witch.
Hunt her down.
- To me.
- Yes, ma'am.
Show yourself, witch.
Do it.
Witch!
I will find you.
You will burn in hell.
You will burn in hell, witch!
The witch that will not hang.
The witch
that will not hang.
The witch that will not hang.
The witch
that will not hang.
The witch that will not hang.
The witch
that will not hang.
The witch that will not hang.
The witch
that will not hang.
The witch that will not hang.
If a man wanted
to ambush another man,
this would be
the perfect spot.
Jump him while his eyes were
still adjusting to the dark.
Maybe even bring three,
four friends.
Make sure the job
got done right.
This thing has never worked.
But this never fails.
Gray Alys.
Did you recognize my footsteps?
No. Your kindness.
This city gets
worse and worse,
but you have always
been so generous
ever since I was a child.
Only to you.
You never ask anything of me.
Strange.
You sound no different
to when I was young,
but you must
be old now like me.
Older.
Much older.
- I'm Jerais.
- Captain of the Overwatch.
Have you come on behalf
of the Overlord?
Or perhaps his queen?
What brings you
to visit one like me?
It is said that for a price,
you grant wishes.
What do you wish to buy?
Leave us.
I'm not sure if that is wise.
Some say you came
from the Lost Lands
and that you know the things
that live there.
Dark, unnatural things.
Is this what
you want from me?
To tell you fairy tales?
I want from you the power
to become a beast, Gray Alys.
To be more than human.
Does that shock you?
I have seen too much
to be shocked so easily.
So you can sell me
the secret of shapeshifting?
To a wolf?
Are you certain you want
what you ask for?
You might not be happy
with what you receive.
- This is not your concern.
- I am compelled to help.
- But I warn all who come to me.
- I'm not all.
- Mm.
- Will you accept my offer?
I refuse no one.
I'll hire a hunter.
We'll find you a shapeshifter
and take its power.
Give me until the full moon
and I will bring you
what you desire.
Where will you go?
To the Lost Lands.
What is it, Jerais?
Do you refuse no one?
No one.
Then accept it as my payment.
I wish to buy for myself.
This timepiece has been
in my family for generations.
It's my most valuable
possession.
And what do you wish for?
I want you to fail her.
The Overwatch
is sworn to loyalty,
yet you betray your queen.
I am loyal.
I know what's good for her
better than she knows herself.
This power that she seeks
will destroy her.
I only want to help.
You lie, Jerais.
You reek of jealousy.
I will not argue with you.
If you will not sell to me,
I will leave.
I refuse no one.
You shall have
what you want.
Argh!
I'm sorry.
What is it you want?
Help me.
Shit.
Did you wet yourself again?
Can't you use the bell,
you old disgusting fool?
The mighty Overlord.
Hard to believe
you built all this.
And that they still fear you.
You're nothing more
than a filthy pig,
just like all men.
My queen?
All men, except for one.
Don't leave yet.
I have to.
Before they see me.
I can't stay here.
Hurry back. Please.
I will.
Perhaps.
Halt, in the name
of the Overlord.
What are you doing here?
The stronger the spirits,
the weaker the senses.
You're coming with us.
Stop!
That was half full.
I hear you're a hunter,
that you travel the Lost Lands.
I have use of such a man.
Came here to play cards,
not to talk.
All in.
You ready to talk now?
What's your name?
Boyce.
I'm looking for a guide.
Someone who knows
the Lost Lands.
- I'm expensive.
- I have money.
I know you do.
Most of it's mine.
Are you worth it?
Would you be here
talking to me if I wasn't?
The Lost Lands
are no place for city folk.
Why is that?
Because they're weak.
Do I look weak to you?
Look.
Outside these walls,
the laws of the city,
of man, even of nature,
they don't apply.
So whoever
you think you are here,
out there you'd
just be a hindrance.
Let's make a deal.
If I ever slow you down,
you have my permission
to leave me behind.
And I'll do the same to you.
Why do you want
to leave the city?
I'm looking for a man
who can turn into a beast.
All men are beasts.
But not all men are monsters.
You're looking
for a shapeshifter.
Yes. I need to kill it
in its lair to take its power.
I've heard of such a man.
What do you know of him?
They call him Sardor,
the Great Wolf.
Where does this man,
this Sardor, live?
In a place called Skull River.
Skull River.
That's my destination.
Not many have
travelled there.
- No one's come back.
- Guide me...
and this can be yours.
I've heard of these.
Never seen one.
I'll take it.
And the coin
you stole from me.
You'll receive your payment
once I get to Skull River.
Friends of yours?
Yeah, I don't have
many friends.
Me neither.
Gun!
Argh!
Find them.
That bitch killed my snake!
No one shall defy the Church.
It is the Church
that protects the peace
of this city with its laws.
The Church that puts fear
into the hearts of the godless.
The Church that keeps the evils
of the Lost Lands at bay.
We are God's instruments,
placed on this earth to
protect you from such evils.
Hunt down the sinners,
the heretics, and the witches.
Bring them to me
and you shall be rewarded.
Gray Alys, with a man.
They left the city together.
The people lose respect for us.
"The witch that will not hang."
Gray Alys has become
a symbol of their defiance.
She left you alive on
that cross to humiliate us.
This woman needs to die.
There is another matter.
- What is this?
- Tell him.
Tell him.
A man and a woman
went to see her.
I heard their names.
It was Jerais and the queen.
If the queen has been
consorting with a heretic,
it would be her downfall.
Make sure the witch
makes a full confession
before she hangs.
No mistakes.
No good.
Never saw a man get emotional
about a snake before.
I'm not emotional, it just--
It was a damn good snake,
that's all.
Here. The pin was bent.
It should work well now.
As long as you stop
beating men to death with it.
A clever man might choose
to kill his client on the road
and take his payment early.
But no one ever accused me
of being a clever man.
This is Ross's place.
He and his sister Mara
are old friends of mine.
Are we?
Hey, Ross.
It's good to see you.
And Mara.
- Welcoming as ever.
- It's been a while.
You look soft.
The City has been
treating you well.
- As have the women, I bet.
- Mm.
Ooh-ooh!
Uh, meet my traveling
companion, Gray Alys.
Welcome.
A friend of Boyce
is a friend of ours.
Gray Alys: The powers
I want from Sardor
will be strongest in his lair.
How much longer
till Skull River?
- A week, maybe longer.
- I need him as a wolf.
So we need to get there
before the full moon.
That won't be easy.
Well, if it was easy,
I wouldn't need you.
The only way would be
following the train tracks.
The tunnels cut
through the mountains.
It'd be dangerous, but we'd
save maybe a day or two.
Yeah.
You need another drink.
Always happy to see me.
It gets boring out here.
Lucky her.
So, who is this woman
you're traveling with?
None of your concern.
Do you like her?
Not the way I like you.
Ah.
Will it be another year
until I see you again?
Mm. If I'm still alive.
One year--a long time
in the Lost Lands.
You come, you go.
I don't know
anything about you.
What do you want to know?
Do you ever get lonely?
I do.
Let me tell you
about loneliness.
Think of a child...
out there in the darkness.
Afraid.
His parents beaten to death...
right in front of his eyes.
The boy travels
the wasteland,
hiding from the outlaws
and the raiders
during the day,
and the creatures
and the ghouls at night.
Till one day
that boy becomes a man,
and his heart
and his mind harden.
But still he travels on,
silently,
scared to get close to anyone
for fear of losing them.
That is loneliness.
And that little boy was you.
No. Hell, no. Of course not.
I've never cried
a day in my life.
You really don t know
anything about me.
Those are the last
friendly faces we'll see.
There's only the Lost Lands
ahead of us now.
What are you doing here?
Offering a prayer for
the Overlord's swift return.
Patriarch, the train
and a large contingent
of your enforcers
have left the city.
- Who authorized this?
- I did.
- Where are they going?
- To catch the witch Gray Alys.
- She is wanted for heresy.
- Your men are needed here.
There is growing unrest
in the streets.
You leave us vulnerable,
Patriarch.
Witchcraft is
punishable by death,
both for the witch
and all who consort with her.
I do not care about her
or what she does.
- And why is that?
- Do not question me.
- I speak for the Overlord.
- Forgive me.
But you are right,
these are dangerous times.
The Overlord's hand
is losing its grip.
I see defiance everywhere.
- And there are rumors.
- What rumors?
- I cannot.
Of your infidelity.
Nothing but lies.
Yes. Vile words spoken
by the basest of tongues.
But even amongst the scum
and rabble, lies have power.
The queen is guilty
of consorting with a witch.
I see it clearly now.
Bring me Gray Alys
and her confession.
I will do the rest.
The Overlord is dying,
and with no heir,
the queen is weak.
Soon, there will be
a new day in the city.
And with the new dawn,
a new Overlord.
Aah! Please!
- God.
- No!
I told you all I know!
Aah! I swear!
No! No! No!
Stop! No!
Skull River!
That's where they're going.
Burn it.
Do you have a family
out here, Boyce?
A home?
The Lost Lands
are a lonely place.
The city, too.
They call it the Rift.
There's a place up ahead where
we can make a safe crossing.
Sirus!
Where you at, old man?
That's my friend's cable car.
Old Sirus will take us over
for a silver coin.
He keeps fresh horses
on the other side.
You're paying.
Sirus?
Wait here.
Boyce?
Seems Sirus had visitors.
So do we.
So you're Boyce. The Hunter.
We asked the old man
if you had already crossed.
He wasn't very helpful.
I always liked Sirus.
Who is that with you, hunter?
None of your tricks, witch.
You can't look us in the eye.
Hand her over
and we'll let you live.
There's a bounty on her head.
Sorry, she hired me first.
A man of principle.
Who'd have thought?
Give us the witch
or you both die.
No.
No one shall defy the Church.
You say you're servants of God?!
What kind of God is this?!
The vengeful kind.
You came here
looking for a monster.
Now you found one.
Boyce...
Behold.
A resurrection.
No!
Boyce, we have to go.
- Argh!
- Let's go!
Quick!
Argh!
Ah!
Cut the cable.
Cut the cable!
Cut it!
Argh!
We have to climb!
Come on!
Argh!
Why didn't she finish me?
She tried.
A witch, indeed.
How do we cross?
We have to go around.
Then let's move.
They'll be headed
for the mountains.
No. Hell is where
they're headed.
You all right?
Drunk.
Hmm!
Thank you.
I could've died back there.
No, you couldn't.
Not until you get me
to Skull River.
Okay. I'm ready.
Would you mind
stitching me up?
Of course.
I think I'd like
to pass out now.
Nice work.
Still hurts.
Drink this.
You're thinking
about your friends?
I'm sorry.
Ross was a good man.
Known him a long time.
Mara.
I'm going to kill them
for what they did.
Why do you travel
out here, Boyce?
I love the city, the people.
A strong drink, good food.
Yet a part of me
only feels at home here.
Listening to the wind.
Watching the shadows.
See there, Gray Alys?
See the way the lights
shimmer and shift?
You can see shapes in them
if you look long enough.
Yes.
It's beautiful.
I knew you'd see.
We're alike, you and I.
In our blood.
We're two of a kind.
I could see it in your eyes.
You are pregnant.
You may go now.
Did you hear?
Of course you didn't.
We have an heir.
Not that you had
anything to do with it.
Do you want to know
who the father
of the new Overlord is?
Boyce.
That's his name.
A simple hunter.
I once was
a simple girl myself.
Look at me now.
The train.
We'll need to take the pass
or they'll run us down.
It'll be dangerous.
When night falls,
demons roam these mountains.
We have no choice.
This is where
we make a stand.
Help me with these.
We need a fire all night.
Flame is the only thing
they fear.
We don't have long.
Prepare yourself.
Here they come.
Gray Alys.
You should not have
come back here.
Leave him.
Boyce!
Help me! Boyce!
The fire from your hands,
I didn't feel it.
There was no fire.
It couldn't have hurt us.
But to them the illusion
was real enough.
Why do you suffer then?
The powers I wield
come at a price.
I heard the monster
talking to you.
Gray Alys: He knew me.
A long time ago.
How?
There is a great treasure
inside of this place.
An immense power.
A man came to me.
He was greedy,
power hungry.
They all are.
But I can refuse no one,
so I helped him.
But this place is poison.
It turned him and his men
into what you saw.
He shouldn't have
asked me for help.
No one should ever
ask me for help.
I should just be left alone.
You're with me now.
There are tracks
to the west.
They are close.
The Overlord is dead,
but the queen is with child!
All hail the new Overlord!
The Overlord is dead!
All hail the new Overlord.
And all hail the queen.
All hail the queen.
Hail the Overlord
and hail the queen.
Thank you, Patriarch.
Now we both
have what we wanted.
You have your heir
and I have his power.
16 years until your child
will be of age.
We couldn't ask
for his authority
to be in better hands.
You are too kind.
I wouldn't have
anything, Patriarch,
not without your wise advice
and unfailing support.
- I hope that will never change.
- Your loyal servant.
Always.
A dirty whore sits upon
the throne of the city.
An affront to all
that is good and pure.
Our time is running out.
Her power grows stronger
by the day.
Find me the witch.
Bring me her confession.
Then the witch and the whore
will hang together.
But hurry.
Do you hear me? Hurry!
Tomorrow we'll
reach Skull River.
- Will he be there?
- Sardor?
I don't know. I hope not.
I need to face him alone.
Then you will die.
One always has to die.
This is madness.
You should leave.
You did what I paid you to do.
I never should have
accepted your offer.
But you did.
Leave, Boyce.
- Save yourself.
- No.
Forget this. Turn around.
I cannot.
Why?
Because I have no choice.
No one should ever
ask me for help.
Gray.
Come back.
With me.
Don't you understand, Boyce?
I'm cursed.
No one should ever
get close to me.
I don't care.
The Patriarch
calling to the faithful.
This is the moment
we've been working for.
What we've been dreaming of
since we were small,
looking up at this place.
But he can take
it all away from us.
My Overwatch
outnumber his men now.
But he is still dangerous.
Would you do
anything for me?
Anything.
You are my good soldier.
Gray Alys: You're quiet.
Skull River lies up ahead.
They're coming.
We can't outrun 'em.
We won't have to.
- The witch!
- Yes!
Our time is upon us.
Make haste!
Do you hear me?
You will not escape us
this time!
There will be
a new day in the city.
Repent, witch!
No!
Without the witch,
we must take the throne
by force.
Assemble my guard.
Do you hear me?
Brothers! Brothers, to me!
There is no use.
Your brothers are dead.
You heretic.
In the name of the Overlord,
protector of
the City Under The Mountain,
I hereby sentence you,
Patriarch, to death.
Gray Alys: My God.
How many has he killed?
Everyone
that's come against him.
Look at all this.
Someone lives here.
Sardor.
This fire hasn't
been lit in weeks.
Tonight will be
the full moon.
He will come then.
It's not too late
to turn back.
We could leave now.
You think he would let us?
Do you think
he's not watching us?
You could go.
I could hold him back.
No.
It is too late for that.
It will be a full moon tonight.
You're still thinking
about that witch.
She promised me.
You don't need
what she promised.
You have everything now.
Not everything.
Silver?
Silver.
Your weapons will be useless.
They've come against him
with silver.
Silver swords, silver knives,
arrows tipped with silver.
They're all dust now,
all those brave,
silvered warriors.
Please, don't do this.
We have no choice.
I think he's very
close now, Boyce.
What say you?
Not yet.
There's still time, Gray.
I think you lie, hunter!
There was never any Sardor.
Only you.
You knew? You knew what I was?
I cared for you.
All this time,
you tried to deceive me.
You thought
you could bring me here
and kill me like the rest!
You shouldn't have ever
come here--here, Gray Alys.
I tried to warn you.
Argh!
Calm.
You need to rest while
the moon is still covered.
You have a gift I'd kill for.
You change at will,
full moon or not.
No. It was just an illusion.
To distract you,
to leave you vulnerable.
We're the same, Gray.
- Don't you see?
- Yes.
Two of a kind.
You are still weak.
Sleep.
Hmm?
Untie me.
I don't understand.
Why? You saved me.
You would not
like my answer, Boyce.
It's the moon.
Are you afraid of what'll
happen if I change again?
I won't harm you, Gray Alys.
- Not now.
- I do not fear you, Boyce.
I know you too well.
I learned all your
weaknesses along the way.
I even added to them.
What are you talking about?
I'm so sorry.
But your fate was sealed
when you met me.
You were right, Boyce.
Silver weapons
were not enough.
You poisoned me?
I had to put silver
in your blood.
Why didn't
you just let me die?
Because dead things
have no power.
Hey, wait, wait, wait!
You--you have
to grant my wish.
You can refuse no one.
Those are your words.
- What do you wish for, Boyce?
- I want you.
I want us to be together.
I want us to hunt together,
to fight together.
To find an end
to all this loneliness?
Yes, you want it, too,
I know it.
I refuse no one.
But there is a price
to be paid.
Name it. Anything.
Very well.
The witch is back!
Man 2: It's her! It's her!
- She's back!
- She's back! The witch!
The witch that will not hang!
The witch
that will not hang!
The witch that will not hang!
Get back to work!
- The witch that will not hang!
- Down with the Overlord!
Down with the Church!
Down with the Overlord!
Gray Alys: Take this.
Tell the queen to cut herself,
to drip her own blood
onto the skin and wear it.
Tonight will be the end
of the lunar cycle.
She must do it
before the end of the night.
Then the power will be hers.
Wolf skin?
The skin of a shapeshifter
killed in its lair.
Well, Gray Alys, you have
done what she asked of you,
but you have failed me.
I did not pay you for success.
Now, give me
my timepiece back.
No, Jerais. I've earned it.
But I did not get
what I asked for.
But you got
what you wanted.
- And what is that?
- The queen herself.
There was a man,
the father of her child.
You wanted her, but knew
he stood in your way.
I have changed that.
Who was this man?
What was his name?
His name was Boyce.
No!
She killed Boyce!
No, please.
It could never have been.
What are you talking about?
He was a beast.
Beast?
What do you know of it?
He twisted you. You changed.
You did this.
I did what I had to do.
I protected you.
- You betrayed me.
- No, no. I--
You had him killed.
The father of my child!
Oh!
- Please.
- No!
I would do anything for you.
Then die for me.
I did this for you, Boyce.
So we could be together,
hunt together.
The witch that will not hang!
The witch
that will not hang!
The witch that will not hang!
The witch
that will not hang!
The witch that will not hang!
The witch
that will not hang!
The witch that will not hang!
Down with the Overlord!
So, how'd you like my story?
I still don't know how it ends.
Maybe with me
skinning you alive,
just like you did to me.
I'm not sure
I like that ending.
Too bad.
I knew you were
the queen's lover.
- Don't leave yet.
- You know what I am.
- I can't stay here.
- You said the only woman
you could truly love
would be someone like you.
- You are not that.
- But what if I could be?
I want from you the power
to become a beast, Gray Alys.
- I refuse no one.
- I want you to fail her.
- I want you.
I refuse no one.
Gray Alys: I knew
that the queen's desires
would lead to revolution.
And that she would
never wear your skin.
I knew you would live.
You're lying.
Just like I know
that'll misfire.
They say you can buy
anything you might desire
from Gray Alys...
...but it is better not to.
And isn't this
what we wished for?